Guide to the Merrill G. Burlingame Papers 1880-1990
Montana State University Library, Archives and Special Collections, Manuscript Collections
- Organizations, 8
  - Montana Veterans and Pioneers Memorial Building (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Museum associations (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Museum of the Rockies (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Museum of the Rockies (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Museum of the Rockies (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Museum of the Rockies (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Museum of the Rockies (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Museum of the Rockies (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Museum of the Rockies-correspondence (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Museum of the Rockies-Prescott, Gertrude (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Non-partisan League (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - QK club (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Rotary* (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Wool Growers Association (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - World Religions (Box 57, Folder 11)
- Newspaper Clippings, 9
  Newspaper clippings gathered by Burlingame pertaining to a wide variety of subjects represented in other series. These clippings are stored separately due to preservation considerations.
  - Aasheim, T.S. (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Acton, Loren (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - African Violets (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Agriculture (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Alderson family (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Alverson, Jim (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Alzheimer's (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - ACLU (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Anceney, Carles (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Ancient Indians (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Anderson, Marcia (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Archaeology (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Arts and Artists (Box 58, Folder 13)
  - Atkinson, Dr. Alfred (Box 58, Folder 14)
  - Aviation (Box 58, Folder 15)
  - Bannack (Box 58, Folder 16)
  - Bar-X Ranch (Box 58, Folder 17)
  - Barbed wire (Box 58, Folder 18)
  - Barn roof reconstruction (Box 58, Folder 19)
  - Bartolome, Peter W (Box 58, Folder 20)
  - Baucus, Max (Box 58, Folder 21)
  - Bearcreek (Box 58, Folder 22)
  - Beaverhead Rock (Box 58, Folder 23)
  - Beaverslide Stacker (Box 58, Folder 24)
  - Beebe, Margaret S (Box 58, Folder 25)
  - Berrington/Beck (Box 58, Folder 26)
  - Big Horn (Box 58, Folder 27)
  - Big Horn Canyon (Box 58, Folder 28)
  - Big Sky Bible College (Box 58, Folder 29)
  - Big Sky, Montana (Box 58, Folder 30)
  - Big Timber (Box 58, Folder 31)
  - Billings (Box 58, Folder 32)
  - Blakely, Charles P (Box 58, Folder 33)
  - Bobcat sports (Box 58, Folder 34)
  - Bohrer, Randolph (Box 58, Folder 35)
  - Bolles, Martha (Box 58, Folder 36)
  - Boulder Hot Springs (Box 58, Folder 37)
  - Bovey, Charles (Box 58, Folder 38)
  - Boyer brothers, (Willow Creek) (Box 58, Folder 39)
  - Bozeman (Box 58, Folder 40)
  - Bozeman-Banks (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Bozeman-Cemetery (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Bozeman-Churches (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Bozeman-City Manager (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Bozeman Daily Chronicle (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Bozeman-Fire Department (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Bozeman-Firsts (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Bozeman-Gallatin County Detention Center (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Bozeman-Homes (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Bozeman-Hotel (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - Bozeman-Kiwanis (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - Bozeman-Livestock auction (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - Bozeman-Main Street (Box 59, Folder 13)
  - Bozeman-Medicine (Box 59, Folder 14)
  - Bozeman-Senior High prank (Box 59, Folder 15)
  - Bozeman-Streets (Box 59, Folder 16)
  - Bozeman-Sweet Pea (Box 59, Folder 17)
  - Bozeman Trail (Box 59, Folder 18)
  - Bozeman-Water (Box 59, Folder 19)
  - Bozeman-Willson Company (Box 59, Folder 20)
  - Breweries (Box 59, Folder 21)
  - Brewster, Lyman (Box 59, Folder 22)
  - Bridger Canyon, Maiden Rock (Box 59, Folder 23)
  - Broadwater hotel (Box 59, Folder 24)
  - Buchanan, Cynthia (Box 59, Folder 25)
  - Buffalo (Box 59, Folder 26)
  - Bush/Quayle (Box 59, Folder 27)
  - Butte (Box 59, Folder 28)
  - Buttleman, John (Box 59, Folder 29)
  - Camas Hot Springs (Box 59, Folder 30)
  - Cameron (Box 59, Folder 31)
  - Campbell, Tom (Box 59, Folder 32)
  - Cartoons (Ace Reid) (Box 59, Folder 34)
  - Castle (Box 59, Folder 35)
  - Catholic church in Montana (Box 59, Folder 36)
  - Cattle (Box 59, Folder 37)
  - Caves (Box 59, Folder 38)
  - Chesnut (Box 59, Folder 39)
  - Chicago Tribune (Box 59, Folder 40)
  - Chico Hot Springs (Box 59, Folder 41)
  - Child abuse (Box 59, Folder 42)
  - Christian Standard (Box 59, Folder 43)
  - Christler, L.J. (Box 59, Folder 44)
  - Chrome, Montana (Box 59, Folder 45)
  - Churchill (Box 59, Folder 46)
  - Cinnabar (Box 59, Folder 47)
  - Clark, John L (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Clark, Urana (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Clow, Bertha (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Coal (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Coal Tax reinvestment (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - College of Montana (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Colstrip (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Colter, John (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Columbus hospital (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Communism in Montana (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Computers (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Comstock, H.T.P (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Cooke City (Box 60, Folder 13)
  - County schools (Box 60, Folder 14)
  - Cow Chip (Box 60, Folder 15)
  - Crocker, Betty (Box 60, Folder 16)
  - Cushman, Harriette (Box 60, Folder 17)
  - Custer battle (Box 60, Folder 18)
  - Custer, George Armstrong (Box 60, Folder 19)
  - Custer-Sioux skirmish (Box 60, Folder 20)
  - Dams (Box 60, Folder 21)
  - Davis, Cliff (Box 60, Folder 22)
  - Dempsey-Gibbons fight (Box 60, Folder 23)
  - Dimsdale, Thomas (Box 60, Folder 24)
  - Dinosaurs (Box 60, Folder 25)
  - Dry Creek (Box 60, Folder 26)
  - Duncan, John (Box 60, Folder 27)
  - Dusenberry, J. Verne (Box 60, Folder 28)
  - Eagles (Box 60, Folder 29)
  - Eastern Montana (Box 60, Folder 30)
  - Ecton, Zales (Box 60, Folder 31)
  - Education (Box 60, Folder 32)
  - Elections in Montana (Box 60, Folder 33)
  - Elkhorn (Box 60, Folder 34)
  - Elkhorn mine (Box 60, Folder 35)
  - Emery, S.M. (Box 60, Folder 36)
  - Emigrant Gulch (Box 60, Folder 37)
  - Energy Emergency rates (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - English colony (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Erhardt, Tilney W (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Ethnic heritage (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Extension service (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Fishing (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Flag and seal (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Flathead County (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Fletcher, Nellie (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Fligelman, Frieda (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Forests (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Fort Assiniboine (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Fort Belknap (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - Fort Benton (Box 61, Folder 14)
  - Fort Ellis (Box 61, Folder 15)
  - Fort Keogh (Box 61, Folder 16)
  - Fort Logan (Box 61, Folder 17)
  - Fort Peck (Box 61, Folder 18)
  - Fort Shaw (Box 61, Folder 19)
  - Fort Union (Box 61, Folder 20)
  - Foss, Ted (Box 61, Folder 22)
  - Fossil insects (Box 61, Folder 23)
  - Fossils (Box 61, Folder 24)
  - Freedom (Box 61, Folder 25)
  - Fritz, Harry (Box 61, Folder 26)
  - Gallatin Canyon (Box 61, Folder 27)
  - Gallatin City (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Gallatin County (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Gallatin County government (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Gallatin County Rest homes (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Gallatin Field (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Gallatin Gateway (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Gallatin River (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Gallatin Valley (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Gallatin Valley Female Seminary (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Galt, Errol F (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Gambling (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - Gardiner (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - Gass, Sgt. Patrick (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - German POWs (Box 62, Folder 14)
  - Gettysburg Address update (Box 62, Folder 15)
  - Ghost Cliffs (Box 62, Folder 16)
  - Ghost towns (Box 62, Folder 17)
  - Gibbons, General (Box 62, Folder 18)
  - Gibson Park (Box 62, Folder 19)
  - Gilt Edge (Box 62, Folder 20)
  - Giralot vs. Montana State University (Box 62, Folder 21)
  - Graham, Jessica Schultz (Box 62, Folder 22)
  - Great Falls (Box 62, Folder 23)
  - Great Plains (Box 62, Folder 24)
  - Green, Jesse (Box 62, Folder 25)
  - Griffin, Harvey (Box 62, Folder 26)
  - Grizzly bear (Box 62, Folder 27)
  - Grove, Charles Porter (Box 62, Folder 28)
  - Guthrie, A.B. (Box 62, Folder 29)
  - Haines, Aubrey (Box 62, Folder 30)
  - Hainline, Bill (Box 62, Folder 31)
  - Hamilton, Ernst (Box 62, Folder 32)
  - Hangings (Box 62, Folder 33)
  - Hardin (Box 62, Folder 34)
  - Harmann, Joe (Box 62, Folder 35)
  - Havre (Box 62, Folder 36)
  - Haynes Art Gallery (Box 62, Folder 37)
  - Hazardous waste (Box 62, Folder 38)
  - Headwaters Herald (Box 62, Folder 39)
  - Hebgen earthquake (Box 62, Folder 40)
  - Hedges, Cornelius (Box 62, Folder 41)
  - Helena (Box 62, Folder 42)
  - Helena-Carroll Trail (Box 62, Folder 43)
  - Henry's Fork (Box 62, Folder 44)
  - Homesteaders (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Honorary degrees, 1985 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Huffman, Roy (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Huidekoper, Wallis (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Huntley, Chet (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Hutterites (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Indians (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Indians in the Gallatin Valley (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Industry, Montana (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Ingersoll, Wilmer (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Initial Point (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - Iowa, University (Box 63, Folder 12)
  - Jardine (Box 63, Folder 13)
  - Jaw Bone (Box 63, Folder 14)
  - Jennings, Peter (Box 63, Folder 15)
  - John Birch Society (Box 63, Folder 16)
  - Johnson, Sam (Box 63, Folder 17)
  - Judiciary (Box 63, Folder 18)
  - Judith River (Box 63, Folder 19)
  - Keister, Roy M. (Box 63, Folder 20)
  - Kelley, C.F. (Box 63, Folder 21)
  - Kelsey, Bonnie (Box 63, Folder 22)
  - Kelsey, Howard (Box 63, Folder 23)
  - KUSM (Box 63, Folder 24)
  - Labre Indian School (Box 63, Folder 25)
  - Land Grant Colleges (Box 63, Folder 26)
  - Landusky (Box 63, Folder 27)
  - Langhor, Dan (Box 63, Folder 28)
  - Lavina (Box 63, Folder 29)
  - Law (Box 63, Folder 30)
  - Learning disabilities (Box 63, Folder 31)
  - Levinsky, Andrew (Box 63, Folder 32)
  - Lewis and Clark (Box 63, Folder 33)
  - Lewis and Clark Caverns (Box 63, Folder 34)
  - Lewistown (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Literature (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Livesay, Jennie Smith (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Livingston (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Lott Family (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Loy, Myrna (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Lynde, Stan (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - McGee, Warren (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - McGill, Caroline (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - McIntosh, Carl (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - McMullen, Joe (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Madison Buffalo Jump (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - Madison County (Box 64, Folder 13)
  - Magnetic rocks (Box 64, Folder 14)
  - Mammoth Trumpet (Box 64, Folder 15)
  - Manhattan (Box 64, Folder 16)
  - Mansfield, Mike (Box 64, Folder 17)
  - Manufacturing (Box 64, Folder 18)
  - Maps (Box 64, Folder 19)
  - Marino, Joe (Box 64, Folder 20)
  - Mars, Map (Box 64, Folder 21)
  - Martin, Fred (Box 64, Folder 22)
  - Masons (Box 64, Folder 23)
  - Masons (Box 64, Folder 24)
  - Marysville (Box 64, Folder 25)
  - Maurer, Tom (Box 64, Folder 26)
  - Meagher County (Box 64, Folder 27)
  - Meagher, Thomas F. (Box 64, Folder 28)
  - Medicine Wheel (Box 64, Folder 29)
  - Melcher, John (Box 64, Folder 30)
  - Melcher, John (Box 64, Folder 31)
  - Metals (Box 64, Folder 32)
  - Michener (Box 64, Folder 33)
  - Miller, Grace (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Minerals (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Mining (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Missouri River (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Moncrete (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Montana (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Montana-song (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Montana-Bicentennial medal (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Montana-Centennial (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - Montana-Chamber of Commerce (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - Montana-Constitution (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - Montana-Country of the Mountains (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - Montana-Eagle (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - Montana-Education (Box 65, Folder 14)
  - Montana-Flag and seal (Box 65, Folder 15)
  - Montana-Governors' messages (Box 65, Folder 16)
  - Montana-historic trails (Box 65, Folder 17)
  - Montana-Historical calendar (Box 65, Folder 18)
  - Montana-Land trusts (Box 65, Folder 19)
  - Montana-Masonic news (Box 65, Folder 20)
  - Montana-Opinion (Box 65, Folder 21)
  - Montana-Politics (Box 65, Folder 22)
  - Montana-Population (Box 65, Folder 23)
  - Montana-Post (Box 65, Folder 24)
  - Montana-Sapphires (Box 65, Folder 25)
  - Montana State College history (Box 65, Folder 26)
  - Montana state experiment stations (Box 65, Folder 27)
  - MSU (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - MSU 100th Anniversary history (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Montana Talc Company (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Montana Winter Fair (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Montgomery, Joe (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Monuments and markers (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Morely, John Henry (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Mossman (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Movies (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Mueller, Oscar (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - Mullan Road (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - Mullan's expedition (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Museum of the Rockies (Box 66, Folder 13)
  - Museums (Box 66, Folder 14)
  - Myers, Alfred (Box 66, Folder 15)
  - Mysersburg (Box 66, Folder 16)
  - NRTA News bulletin (Box 66, Folder 17)
  - Nesbit, Sidney (Box 66, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper, "Pick and Plow" (Box 66, Folder 19)
  - Newspapers (Box 66, Folder 20)
  - Norris (Box 66, Folder 21)
  - Old Faithful Inn (Box 66, Folder 22)
  - Old Milk River Indian Agency (Box 66, Folder 23)
  - Onstad, Lyle (Box 66, Folder 24)
  - Orient (Box 66, Folder 25)
  - Outpatient business (Box 66, Folder 26)
  - Outstanding Montanans (Box 66, Folder 27)
  - Ova transplant (Box 66, Folder 28)
  - Owen, John (Box 66, Folder 29)
  - Pace, Herb (Box 66, Folder 30)
  - Park County (Box 66, Folder 31)
  - Patagonia (Box 66, Folder 32)
  - Paugh, Minnie (Box 66, Folder 33)
  - Penttila, William (Box 66, Folder 34)
  - Petroleum industry (Box 66, Folder 35)
  - Phillipsburg (Box 66, Folder 36)
  - Photographs and photographers (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Pictographs (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Politics (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Pony (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Print (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Prison (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Railroads (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Rankin, Doris and Barney (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Rankin, Jeannette (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Reagan, Ronald (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - Red Bluff (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - Religious Groups (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - Renne, Roland (Box 67, Folder 13)
  - Retirement (Box 67, Folder 14)
  - Rich, Franklin W (Box 67, Folder 15)
  - Richters, Ken (Box 67, Folder 16)
  - Rick O'Shay (Box 67, Folder 17)
  - Rochester (Box 67, Folder 18)
  - Rocky Boy (Box 67, Folder 19)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Box 67, Folder 20)
  - Rouse, Clifford (Box 67, Folder 21)
  - Ruffner, Sanford (Box 67, Folder 22)
  - Russell, Charles (Box 67, Folder 23)
  - St. Mary's Mission (Box 67, Folder 24)
  - Salesville (Box 67, Folder 25)
  - Salish Falls (Box 67, Folder 26)
  - Sallee Ranch (Box 67, Folder 27)
  - Sand Coulee (Box 67, Folder 28)
  - Sanders, W.F. (Box 67, Folder 29)
  - Sapphire mines (Box 67, Folder 30)
  - Sawmills (Box 67, Folder 31)
  - Schmitt site (Box 67, Folder 32)
  - Schultz, James Willard (Box 67, Folder 33)
  - Seatbelts (Box 67, Folder 34)
  - Semantics (Box 67, Folder 35)
  - Shields River (Box 67, Folder 36)
  - Shodair Hospital (Box 67, Folder 37)
  - Silver statue (Box 67, Folder 38)
  - Sinton, George and Kittie (Box 67, Folder 39)
  - Sitting Bull (Box 67, Folder 40)
  - Skiing (Box 67, Folder 41)
  - Synder, Simon (Box 67, Folder 42)
  - Soldiers Chapel (Box 67, Folder 43)
  - Spokane (Box 67, Folder 44)
  - Springdale Bridge (Box 67, Folder 45)
  - Statue of Liberty (Box 67, Folder 46)
  - Stewart, Katherine (Box 67, Folder 47)
  - Stillwater County (Box 67, Folder 48)
  - Storrs (Box 67, Folder 49)
  - Stream rehabilitation (Box 67, Folder 50)
  - Stuart, Harry C. (Box 67, Folder 51)
  - Sweet Grass Hills (Box 67, Folder 52)
  - Switzer, Malthus (Box 67, Folder 53)
  - Tapes (Box 67, Folder 54)
  - Tindoy (Box 67, Folder 55)
  - Tenth Cavalry (Box 67, Folder 56)
  - Terry (Box 67, Folder 57)
  - Thomas massacre (Box 67, Folder 58)
  - Three Forks (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Three Forks Bicentennial Park (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Three Forks Lewis and Clark pageant (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Toll bridges (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Toole, K. Ross (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Townsend, Elsie Doig (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Townsend (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Tracy, Sarah (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Transportation (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Trident, Post office (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - True, Dave (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - Two Dot (Box 68, Folder 12)
  - UFO (Box 68, Folder 13)
  - Update, Black church (Box 68, Folder 14)
  - Ursulines (Box 68, Folder 15)
  - Vigilantes (Box 68, Folder 16)
  - Virginia City (Box 68, Folder 17)
  - Virginia City (Box 68, Folder 18)
  - Visscher, Wendy (Box 68, Folder 19)
  - Wallace, Bev (Box 68, Folder 20)
  - Water (Box 68, Folder 21)
  - Water Dousers (Box 68, Folder 22)
  - Weather (Box 68, Folder 23)
  - Weatherly, Shannon (Box 68, Folder 24)
  - West Yellowstone (Box 68, Folder 25)
  - Wheeler, Burton K. (Box 68, Folder 26)
  - White, Dudley (Box 68, Folder 27)
  - White Sulphur Springs (Box 68, Folder 28)
  - Wibaux (Box 68, Folder 29)
  - Williams, James (Box 68, Folder 30)
  - Windmill (Box 68, Folder 32)
  - Winter (Box 68, Folder 33)
  - Wolf Point (Box 68, Folder 34)
  - Women (Box 68, Folder 35)
  - World War II (Box 68, Folder 36)
  - Wylie, W.W. (Box 68, Folder 37)
  - Yellowstone County (Box 68, Folder 38)
  - Yellowstone Ecosystem (Box 68, Folder 39)
  - Yellowstone Institute (Box 68, Folder 40)
  - Yellowstone National Park (Box 68, Folder 41)
  - Yellowstone Pine Company (Box 68, Folder 42)
- Personal papers, 10
  Primarily materials created or collected by Burlingame dealing with his personal life, finances, family genealogy, religious topics, awards and commissions, and memorabilia. This series includes speeches that Burlingame gave to community groups on historical and other topics. One file on Ray Burlingame has been closed to research until 2070 by request of the donor.
  - Address lists (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - American West (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Astrapolitics (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Awards and certificates (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Awards and certificates (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Awards and certificates (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - Awards and certificates (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - Background of the Bible (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - Background of the Bible (Box 69, Folder 9)
  - Background of the Bible (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - Biographical information (Box 69, Folder 11)
  - Burlingame family history (Box 69, Folder 12)
  - Christian church (Box 69, Folder 13)
  - Christmas cards (Box 69, Folder 14)
  - Dissertation rewrites (Box 69, Folder 15)
  - Dissertation rewrites (Box 69, Folder 16)
  - Doran/Gildea genealogy (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Ethical and political speeches (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Ethical and political speeches (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Ethical and political speeches (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Funeral arrangements (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Gildea family history (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - History of Canada (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - Masonic aprons (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 70, Folder 10)
  - Montana speeches (Box 70, Folder 11)
  - National influences on the development of Montana (Box 70, Folder 12)
  - Personal library (Box 70, Folder 13)
  - Personal library (Box 70, Folder 14)
  - Poetry and epigram snips (Box 70, Folder 15)
  - Poetry and epigram snips (Box 70, Folder 16)
  - Popularizing Peace (Box 70, Folder 17)
  - Ray Burlingame [RESTRICTED UNTIL 2070] (Box 70, Folder 18)
  - Religious speeches (Box 70, Folder 19)
  - Religious tracts (Box 70, Folder 20)
  - Small Town Renaissance (Box 70, Folder 21)
  - Texas as she is (Box 70, Folder 22)
- Photographs, 11
  Original and copy photographs taken or collected by Burlingame on a wide variety of subjects represented in other series. Topics include: Merrill Burlingame and the Burlingame family; Montana biographical subjects; Montana communities; Bozeman and Gallatin County; the Bozeman Christian Church; Indians and related archaeology; Gustavus C. Doane; Harriette Cushman; and Montana views. The photographs have been arranged topically and have been sequentially numbered. Available negatives have been placed in folder.
  - Burlingame portraits; photographs #1-7, 1903-1934 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Burlingame portraits; photographs #8-16, 1940-1980 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Burlingame-Montana Historical Society; photographs #17-21 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Burlingame family snapshots; photographs #22-43 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Merrill G. Burlingame and Jack Haynes, 1953 (Box 71, Folder 4, Photographic-print 22)
    - Merrill G. Burlingame at Waputki National Monument (Box 71, Folder 4, Photographic-print 23)
    - Merrill G. Burlingame at banquet (Box 71, Folder 4, Photographic-print 24)
    - Merrill G. Burlingame in parade (Box 71, Folder 4, Photographic-print 25)
    - Merrill G. Burlingame, circa 1985 (Box 71, Folder 4, Photographic-print 26)
    - Merrill G. Burlingame family at Yellowstone, 1980 (Box 71, Folder 4, Photographic-print 27-29)
    - Merrill G. Burlingame at Frank Weaver home, 1981 (Box 71, Folder 4, Photographic-print 30-33)
    - Burlingame relatives (Box 71, Folder 4, Photographic-print 38)
    - Burlingame home, Bozeman (Box 71, Folder 4, Photographic-print 39)
    - Burlingame home, Iowa (Box 71, Folder 4, Photographic-print 40)
    - Burlingame Long Distance Relay Machines (Box 71, Folder 4, Photographic-print 42)
    - Burlingame Long Distance Relay Machines (Box 71, Folder 4, Photographic-print 43)
  - Montana State University/Montana State College #44-64 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Crew, Clara (Box 71, Folder 5, Photographic-print 44)
    - Comstock, Henry T (Box 71, Folder 5, Photographic-print 45)
    - Hapner, William (Box 71, Folder 5, Photographic-print 46)
    - Hapner, William (Box 71, Folder 5, Photographic-print 47)
    - King, Thomas Wylie (Box 71, Folder 5, Photographic-print 48-56)
    - Koch, Peter (Box 71, Folder 5, Photographic-print 57)
    - Koch, Peter (Box 71, Folder 5, Photographic-print 58)
    - Missoula High School graduation, 1915 (Box 71, Folder 5, Photographic-print 59)
    - Monroe, B.K. (Box 71, Folder 5, Photographic-print 60)
    - Rich, Franklin W. (Box 71, Folder 5, Photographic-print 61)
    - Rich, Franklin W., Mrs. (Box 71, Folder 5, Photographic-print 62)
    - Smith, Scott L. (Box 71, Folder 5, Photographic-print 63)
    - Tuttle, Daniel S (Box 71, Folder 5, Photographic-print 64)
  - Montana towns #65-92 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Baker, 1920 (Box 71, Folder 6, Photographic-print 65)
    - Baker, 1920 (Box 71, Folder 6, Photographic-print 66)
    - Baker, 1920 (Box 71, Folder 6, Photographic-print 67)
    - Deer Lodge (Box 71, Folder 6, Photographic-print 68)
    - Deer Lodge (Box 71, Folder 6, Photographic-print 69)
    - Deer Lodge (Box 71, Folder 6, Photographic-print 70)
    - Eureka, 1915 (Box 71, Folder 6, Photographic-print 71)
    - Eureka, 1915 (Box 71, Folder 6, Photographic-print 72)
    - Gallatin City, circa 1939 (Box 71, Folder 6, Photographic-print 73-78)
    - Helena (Box 71, Folder 6, Photographic-print 80-84)
    - Phillipsburg (Box 71, Folder 6, Photographic-print 85)
    - Manhattan, 1925 (Box 71, Folder 6, Photographic-print 86-89)
    - Pony (Box 71, Folder 6, Photographic-print 90-92)
  - Three Forks #93-100 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Aerial views (Box 71, Folder 7, Photographic-print 93-100)
  - Three Forks #101-112 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Gravesite (Box 71, Folder 8, Photographic-print 101)
    - Dog sled (Box 71, Folder 8, Photographic-print 102)
    - Miner (Box 71, Folder 8, Photographic-print 103)
    - Cabin (Box 71, Folder 8, Photographic-print 104)
    - Bicentennial Celebration, 1976 (Box 71, Folder 8, Photographic-print 105-112)
  - Bozeman #113-126 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Gallatin High School class, circa 1930s (Box 71, Folder 9, Photographic-print 113)
    - Bozeman Women's Missionary Society, 1911 (Box 71, Folder 9, Photographic-print 114)